Fail Safe is a drama, thriller, tv movie film directed by Stephen Frears.
Cold War tensions climb to a fever pitch when a U.S.
bomber is accidentally ordered to drop a nuclear warhead on Moscow.
Self - Host, played by Walter Cronkite.
President, played by Richard Dreyfuss.
Buck, played by Noah Wyle.
Gen. Bogan, played by Brian Dennehy.
Congressman Raskob, played by Sam Elliott.
Gordon Knapp, played by James Cromwell.
Fail Safe is a 2000 televised broadcast play, directed by Stephen Frears and based on
Fail-Safe, the Cold War novel  by Eugene Burdick and Harvey Wheeler.
The play, broadcast live in black and white on CBS, starred George Clooney, Richard Dreyfuss, Harvey Keitel, and Noah
Wyle, and was one of the few live dramas on American television since its Golden Age in the 1950s and 1960s.
The broadcast was introduced by Walter Cronkite; his introduction, also broadcast
in black and white, is included in the DVD releases of the film.
The novel was first adapted into a 1964 film of the same name directed by Sidney Lumet; the TV version
is shorter than the 1964 film due to commercial airtime and omits a number of subplots.
The film explores themes of usa president, based on novel or
book, nuclear war, atomic bomb, cold war.
The tone is emotional and intense.